<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moshe Poliak</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Moshe Poliak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: moshepol[at]mit[dot]edu Twitter LinkedIn  Fun Fact:  Some words are regular travelers, going on vacation abroad and returning with a new accent. Consider the Arabic dār al-ṣināʿa (literally, house of manufacture; a factory). It was borrowed into Latin around the middle of the previous millenium as arsana, eventually becoming the word we know in English as arsenal. Not quite a place of production, but a place for storage of weapons (&amp;ldquo;arsenal, n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moshe Poliak</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student in Brain and Cognitive Sciences at MIT. My advisor is Ted Gibson. I study psycholinguistics, or what processes in the mind are involed in language production and comprehension. Specifically, I study how we use non-lexical properties of language in comprehension and production. Using the noisy channel framework, I investigate how expectations about the formof the utterance affects how we interpret it. I am also trying to figure out what exactly makes two utterances similar to each other, in speech and in writing, and how this depends on individual differences in linguistic background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications (work in progress :-) )
Posters &amp;amp; Abstracts Chen, A.*, Hofer, M.*, Poliak, M., Zaslavsky, N., &amp;amp; Levy R. (2022). The emergence of discrete and systematic communication in a continuous signal–meaning space. Poster at the 44 Annual Meeting of Cognitive Science Society (CogSci).
Poliak, M., Ryskin, R., Braginsky, M., &amp;amp; Gibson, E. (2022). Effects of the structural prior on noisy-channel inference: evidence from Russian. Poster at the 35th Annual Conference in Human Sentence Processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Grad School Applications My grad school application process was greatly facilitated by having access to amazing resources. As an undergrad at Harvard, I had access to influential professors both at Harvard and elsewhere, kind and knowledgeable grad student mentors, courses at other institutions, funding for travel and research, and so on. I am endlessly grateful to all those people who worked very hard to help me. At the same time, this underscores how much privilege I have and how much an uneven playing field grad school applications are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
