<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moshe Poliak</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Moshe Poliak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: moshepol[at]mit[dot]edu Twitter LinkedIn  Personal Note:  Do not hesitate to write to me if you think I can help: I urge you to do it. Throughout my life, I have been spoiled with divine mentors; but so many people do not get to be as lucky as I have. You can write to me about science, immigration, queerness, academia, college, or anything else that&amp;rsquo;s on your mind. I want to help if I can and pay forward the kindness that has been shown to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moshe Poliak</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student in Brain and Cognitive Sciences at MIT. My advisor is Ted Gibson, which means that I am a very lucky person. I study psycholinguistics, or what processes in the mind are involved in language production and comprehension. Using the noisy channel framework, I apply one of the most fundamental questions in psychology to language: how do my expectation about the world shape how I make sense of it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications Poliak, M., Ryskin, R., Braginsky, M., &amp;amp; Gibson, E. (2023). It is not what you say but how you say it: Evidence from Russian shows robust effects of the structural prior on noisy channel inferences. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition.
Posters &amp;amp; Abstracts Poliak, M., Malik-Moraleda, S., &amp;amp; Gibson E. (2024) Sentence Processing Relies on Expectations Regarding Both Meaning and Structure. Poster at the LSA Annual Convention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Grad School Applications My grad school application process was greatly facilitated by having access to amazing resources. As an undergrad at Harvard, I had access to influential professors both at Harvard and elsewhere, kind and knowledgeable grad student mentors, courses at other institutions, funding for travel and research, and so on. I am endlessly grateful to all those people who worked very hard to help me. At the same time, this underscores how much privilege I have and how much an uneven playing field grad school applications are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
